

SAGAR THAPLIYAL

Web Developer

4387256804 · sagarwipro143@gmail.com

Portfolio, LinkedIn, Github

Skills

PHP

CSS

Figma

HTML5

Window OS

Microsoft Outlook

Internet Browsing

JavaScript

Customer Service

IT Troubleshooting

Communication Skills

Visual Studio Code

Java Programming

Unix Administrator

React JS

MySql

Database Design

Languages

English

Hindi

Hobbies

Playing Badminton, Table Tennis, Reading Blogs, Playing Video Games, Dancing and Singing.

Profile

Dedicated web developer with two years of experience in front-end and back-end development. Motivated designer and developer with experiences in creating custom websites through JS, React, PHP, MySQL and HTML/CSS. Strong collaboration skills and proven history of application development. Hardworking Developer gifted at turning prospects into clients and delivering exceptional RESTful APIs. Engaging, personable and focused on delivering Web designs. Outstanding developer with adaptable in new technologies, styles and success in collaborating across organizational levels. Focused on helping resolve business issues and capitalize on development opportunities.

Employment History

Trainee Programmer, Aptara, Dehradun

July 2013 - January 2014

Job brief

Producing the monthly newsletter, fact-checking writers' articles and optimizing written pieces to increase user engagement. I had excellent writing and editing skills in English and experience managing editorial calendars.

Responsibilities

- · Write blog posts and marketing copy to promote our products and services
- Proofread, re-structure and edit articles by content writers
- Update our website and social media pages with new content
- · Craft and send our monthly newsletter
- Interview industry professionals and use online sources to research topics
- Improve illustration in collaboration with marketing and design teams
- Optimize published pieces using SEO guidelines
- Manage the editorial calendar and ensure timely publication
- · Generate new ideas around industry-related topics
- Monitor web traffic and user engagement (e.g. bounce rates)

Project Engineer, Wipro Technologies, Bengaluru

November 2014 - May 2017

Job brief

Job to do cloud computing services for our Nokia developers. As a cloud administrator, my job duties were to transition locally hosted infrastructture to the cloud, configure cloud environments to meet Nokia Siemens.

Responsibilities

- Monitoring around 1000 clouds located in Bengaluru(India),
- Espoo, China and Finland via different tools.
- Handling Service Requests and Incident tickets within SLA.
- Offering the virtual components like volumes, CPUs, Memory and
- scaling the image with desired components.
- Making scripts to run jobs in specific times that saves hours of many employee and increase the productivity.
- Documentation of specific issue for future reference.
- Delivering support to internal teams by carrying expected job responsibilities.
- Bachelor's degree in computer science, computer engineering, or a similar field.
- Previous experience as a UNIX system administrator.
- Knowledge of UNIX and LINUX operating systems, storage environments, file systems, and network protocols.
- Detailed knowledge of UNIX principles, file editing, UNIX commands, and file manipulation.
- Familiarity with Windows, UNIX, LINUX, and LINUX shell scripting.
- Knowledge of networking principles including routing, subnets, TCP, IP, VLANs, and UDP.
- Understanding of backup procedures and storage management.
- In-depth knowledge of computer hardware systems including circuit boards, memory modules, and processors.
- Excellent troubleshooting skills.

Associate Web Designer, Proponent Technologies, Dehradun

August 2017 - May 2019

Job brief

I was coding for innovative designs and layouts for our projected websites. My main responsibilities included building website from concept all the way to completion from the bottom up, fashioning everything from the home page to site layout and function.

Responsibilities

- Converting design from Figma into react js codes for the back-end developer.
- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, JavaScript, AJAX and JSON coding.
- Provided front-end website development using Figma, Dribbler and other editing software.
- Conducted functional testing over course of web development lifecycle.
- Coded websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery languages.
- Ran debugging tools such as Firebug and Chrome Inspector to eliminate flaws and glitches prior to publishing.
- Oversaw back-end development using PHP to maintain website integrity, security and efficiency.
- Stay plugged into emerging technologies/industry trends and apply them into operations and activities
- Cooperate with web developers to match visual design intent.
- Pulled from PHP, SQL, JavaScript and other back-end library knowledge to bolster programming resources.

- Be responsible for maintaining, expanding, and scaling our site.
- Developing Designs for the LMS and internal websites.
- Documents the templates for different sites for final approval.
- Built and styled new mobile-friendly websites, transitioning legacy presentations to simultaneous easy-to-use versions.

Consultant, CGI, Montreal

September 2021 — February 2022

Job Brief

Working with hardware and software vendors to verify timely product delivery and ensuring that new equipment is installed and ready to operate on schedule. Analyzing and resolving issues related to hardware and software with many existing standardization procedures and policies.

Suncor, Level 1 technician

- Diagnose, troubleshoot and resolve incidents or service requests reported by the client;
- Diagnose and resolve technical hardware and software issues (printer, cell phone, web browser, MS Office Suite, etc.);
- Resolve technical problems in different Microsoft Windows Operating Systems;
- Leverage appropriate tools for diagnostics, troubleshooting and resolution activities (remote takeover, knowledge base, ticketing tool, communication tools);
- Log, document all troubleshooting steps and resolution activities within the incident management tool;
- Monitor incidents until resolution;
- Follow standard service desk procedures;
- Assign non-resolved incidents or service requests to the appropriate support team, identify and escalate incidents requiring urgent attention and action;
- Stay current with system information, changes and updates;
- Technical support for:

Active Directory; Microsoft Office; Microsoft Exchange; VPN; Symantec; McAfee EMM / BES 12 / BlackBerry UEM; SAP; BETC (BELL ENTERPRISE TOTAL CONNECT); Internet browsers (Internet Explorer, Chrome, Firefox); Dameware, SCCM; AVAYA; Citrix; SingleView; OneBill

· Equipements:

Desktop; Printers; Mobiles devices.

Use of ticketing systems like ITSM, ServiceNow.

Education

Bachelor of Computer Application, OIMT, Rishīkesh

June 2010 — July 2013

Web Development, ISI, L'institut Supérieur d'Informatique, Montreal

Internships

Web Developer, Esky.ca, Montreal

August 2021 - February 2022

Description

Developing Designs for the LMS for Buston and internal websites on Figma, Dribbler and other tools.

Converting design into codes for the back end developer.

Understanding the requirement of design from team leader and apply ideas on the ground.

Documents the templates for different sites for final approval.

References

Beshoy Soliman from esky.ca beshoysoliman11@gmail.com

Manish Bhatt from Proponent Technologies +91 9410771660 · info@proponenttechnologies.com

Shanmugam from Wipro Technologies +91 9940644806

 $\ensuremath{\mathbb{I}}$ Fillion-Ghio, Vincenzo from CGI Inc.

+1 819 620 3587 · vincenzo.fillion-ghio@cgi.com